( light grandeur music )
( calm music )
( light eerie music )
- [ Sasha ] You 're listening to Under the Covers
with Sasha on WZAB , the voice of Pendleton University .
We 're still talking to ... - Jane .
Sophomore .
Hi .
- [ Sasha ] So , you 've been stealing
your roommate 's birth control pills ?
- [ Jane ] Borrowing , okay ?
Well , she never noticed before
' cause I 've always replaced them with baby aspirin .
- [ Sasha ] With what ?
- [ Jane ] Baby aspirin .
Looks exactly the same .
Anyway , so now she 's pregnant and has to leave school .
How the hell am I gonna get
a new roommate this late in the semester ?
( intense music )
( horn blaring ) ( brakes screeching )
- Oh , my God !
- [ Sasha ] Next caller .
♪ Now and then I get a little bit tired ♪
♪ Of listening to the sound of my tears ♪
♪ Turn around ♪
♪ Every now and then I get a little bit nervous ♪
♪ That the best of all the years have gone by ♪
♪ Turn around ♪
♪ Every now and then I get a little bit terrified ♪
♪ But then I see the look in your eyes ♪
♪ Turn around bright eyes ♪
♪ Every now and then I fall apart ♪
♪ And I need you now tonight ♪
♪ And I need you more than ever ♪
♪ More than ever ♪
♪ And if you only hold me tight ♪
♪ We 'll be homing on forever ♪
♪ And we 'll only be making it right ♪
♪ ' Cause we 'll never be wrong together ♪
♪ We can take it to the end of the line ♪
- Oh , no .
( alert lightly ringing )
Shit .
Okay , please , please make it .
( bell dinging )
( horn honking )
( dramatic music )
- Run outta gas ?
- Yeah .
Fill it up , please .
Freak show .
- ( stutters ) Miss , could you come inside for a minute ?
Please ! - What is it ?
- Your credit card company 's on the phone .
- Is there a problem ?
- They wanna speak with you .
- Okay , hold on a minute .
Shit .
( dial tone beeping ) Hello ?
( dramatic music )
No , don 't touch me !
Let me go !
( man screaming )
- Stop !
( car alarm blaring )
Stop !
Someone 's in the back seat !
( woman softly crying )
♪ Every now and then I get a little bit nervous ♪
♪ That the best of all the years have gone ♪
♪ Turn around ♪
♪ Every now and then I get a little bit terrified ♪
♪ And then I see the look in your eyes ♪
♪ Turn around bright eyes ♪
♪ Every now and then I fall apart ♪
( glass shattering )
( clock bells ringing )
( soft jazz music )
- [ Sasha ] You 're Under the Covers with Sasha on WZAB ,
the voice of Pendleton University .
Caller .
- [ Caller ] Hello ?
- I 'm right here .
Felicia , how can I help you ?
- [ Felicia ] Well , it 's kind of embarrassing .
- Spit it out , Felicia .
- [ Felicia ] Well , that 's just the problem .
I mean , I didn 't .
- Ah , had yourself a little frat boy protein shake , did ya ?
- [ Felicia ] Sasha , I 've been feeling so sick .
I mean , swear , I can feel them swimming inside me .
Should I get my stomach pumped or something ?
- Felicia , I think the only thing you need pumped
is the air out of your head .
First , let me just congratulate you
on your choice of sexual activity
because , sweetie , the world is not ready
for you to reproduce .
Second , did you know that ingestion of bodily fluids
is a major safe sex no-no ?
- Really ? - Really .
My suggestion is that you down
a couple shots of Pepto and next time ,
get away from the volcano before it erupts .
That wraps up another night .
This is Sasha signing off on WZAB .
- Parker , how exactly does Sasha come up with this stuff ?
- She devours every issue of Cosmo .
Calls it her Bible .
- Thank you .
So , Parker finish the story about Stanley Hall .
- Right .
So , this guy , he was a professor on campus ,
maybe 25 years ago .
- What did he teach ? - I don 't know .
Physics or some shit .
- Abnormal Psychology .
You know , if you wanna tell the story right .
- Not the point of the story , paperboy !
But fine .
Abnormal Psych it is .
Anywho .
This guy , he just flips out , you know ?
Goes completely berserk .
Grabs a hunting knife and he strolls into Stanley Hall .
Bangs on every door .
( loudly banging )
And every student that answers their door ,
he takes that little knife ,
and he cuts their throat ear to ear .
Yeah .
He does away with an entire floor
before finally stabbing himself straight through the heart .
And thus , the annual Omega Sigma Phi bash .
- So you have a frat party to commemorate a massacre ?
- You betcha .
- Parker , let me get this straight .
When this happened 25 years ago ,
you were a sophomore .
- That 's funny .
- Well , it 's a bullshit story you hear
on every campus in the northeast .
- Thank you .
I mean , where 's the proof ?
- You see , that 's the thing .
Pendleton knew damn well
that enrollment would suffer permanently .
So , in cahoots with the national news media
and various other powerful ... - Like Lee Harvey Oswald ?
Or is it Jack Ruby ?
No , no , I know who it was .
It was that F.B.I. guy who used to
prance around in women 's underwear .
He 's the guy that covered it all up , huh ?
( pager beeping )
Oh , that 's the news room .
I gotta go .
Get a life . - Hey , Paul !
- Yeah .
- Before you go , if there 's another E. coli crisis
in the cafeteria , I want you to have
the biggest , juiciest burger on me .
- I 'd love to .
That article almost got me the student Pulitzer .
- Bye , Paul .
Know what his problem is ?
He can 't stand any big story
without having his byline on it .
- He is such a babe .
All right ?
Did it seem like he was giving me the eye ?
- It was probably the mirror behind us .
- Oh , damn .
Should I ask him out anyway ?
Okay , if Parker 's story is true
and all those kids were murdered here ,
why haven 't they torn down Stanley Hall ?
- [ Natalie ] Because the story 's not true .
It 's just a legend .
- [ Brenda ] If it 's just a legend , then what 's the problem ?
- [ Natalie ] I won 't encourage this .
- Come on , Natalie .
Cut me a little slack .
This is half the reason I transferred here .
Now what exactly happens
when I say Bloody Mary five times ?
- The person standing next to you wonders
how you got into college in the first place .
Come on . - You 're scared , Natalie .
- Yeah , right .
- Then come on and let 's do this .
Come on !
Time to raise the dead !
- [ Natalie ] I can 't believe this .
- Okay . - Okay .
- Bloody Mary . ( both chuckling )
Bloody Mary .
Bloody Mary . - Bloody Mary .
( eerie music ) Fine .
No answer .
Maybe they 're screening .
- God .
( distant yelling )
( screeching )
Let 's go , Natalie . - Yeah .
( distant screeching )
( sharp dramatic music ) ( girls screaming )
- You called ?
- She was trying to summon the dead , Damon ,
not frat boys with badly grown facial hair .
- It took me a month to grow this .
- So is this what you do with your free time , Damon ?
Just hang out in the dark by yourself ,
waiting to scare people like a total freak .
- Only when I see two losers
stand in front of this relic , trying to summon the dead .
Anyhow , I 'll see you two in class tomorrow .
- Unfortunately ! - See ya .
- Jerk .
- You know , he was halfway normal before pledge week .
( sharp dramatic music )
Oh , ( chuckles ) sorry .
( loud rock music )
- Shut off the fucking light .
- Sorry .
( loud rock music )
♪ Close my eyes ♪
( both loudly groaning )
( light music )
- Last week , we discussed folklore as a gauge
for the values of the society that created them .
Today .
Today , we get more specific .
A baby-sitter receives menacing phone calls .
And upon investigating them ,
she realizes that they are originating
from an upstairs bedroom ,
the very room where she 's left the children
under her care to sleep .
Now , who 's heard this before ?
- Well , that really happened to a girl in my hometown .
- ( laughs ) Oh , yes .
I 'm sure it did .
I 'm sure most of you grew up thinking
this did happen to girls in all your hometowns ,
but it didn 't .
You see , the baby-sitter and the man upstairs
is what we call an urban legend .
Contemporary folklore passed on as a true story .
Now , there are variations of this one
going back to the 1960s ,
all of them containing the same cultural admonition :
Young women , mind your children or harm will come your way .
( phone ringing )
Excuse me ?
( Brenda laughing )
Something funny you might care to share with us , Ms. ?
- No , I was just saying , like ,
maybe the cultural admonition is : Don 't baby-sit .
( class laughing )
- Why don 't you come up here and volunteer
for my little experiment , hmm ?
- Yeah , that 's a great idea .
- Now , young lady !
- Coming .
- Yeah , baby .
- Don 't worry .
You 'll probably survive .
Had those before ?
- Yeah , they 're Pop Rocks .
They crackle in your mouth .
- Eat some .
Thirsty ?
Well , what 's wrong ?
Something you might have heard
about mixing Pop Rocks and soda ?
- Well , supposedly your stomach and your intestines ,
everything bursts .
- Really ?
Anyone you know who died this way ?
- Mikey , from the cereal commercial .
Give it to Mikey .
He 'll eat anything .
- You mean him ?
- Mikey likes it . ( class laughing )
- [ Brenda ] Yeah .
- What if I told you that this is Mikey ,
alive and well and working as an ad executive
in New York City ?
Would you drink some then ?
- I 'll do it .
- Your soda .
Voila !
Still alive .
As I said , class , this story is nothing but an urban legend .
( ominous music )
Woops .
- [ Student ] Professor !
- He 's going to explode ! ( Brenda screaming )
Somebody call 9-1-1 !
Go !
( dramatic music )
- Thank you for your help .
- Brilliant .
He 's brilliant .
- [ Brenda ] He is such a moron .
- Yeah , but who fell for it ?
- Hey , what 's going on ?
Excuse me , young man .
Can 't read these . - She just left the campus .
- [ Natalie ] She went to Pendleton ?
- You have got to be kidding me .
I knew I should 've gone to N.Y.U.
- Tragic , huh ?
- Hi , Paul .
- Hey .
- Is this true ?
- I certainly hope so .
Otherwise I 'm gonna have one hell
of a retraction on my hands .
Hey !
What do you think you 're doin ' ?
You can 't just come and take every copy here .
- You 're the one that wrote
this inflammatory piece of rubbish .
- Well , actually , the fatuous quotes
about being deeply shocked and heartsick
are yours , Dean Adams .
- Let me tell you something , young man .
The only lunatic on this campus is you .
- I 'm flattered .
Can I quote you on that ?
- I have a quote for ya .
U.S. News and World Report named Pendleton
the safest university in this country .
And you best believe , I intend to keep it that way .
- Thank you , Reese .
I 'll make sure and stick that
in the special school safety edition .
- [ Natalie ] Let 's get out of here .
- Hey , hold on a second .
How about some interviews , you know ?
Students react to the tragedy on campus .
- Okay , I am saddened and moved by ...
- This was someone 's life , Paul .
Did you even spend one minute thinking about that ?
- No , I didn 't .
But because of my story , 3,500 students will ,
I think that 's enough to help me sleep at night .
- Come on , let 's go .
- Natalie , wait !
- The decapitated body of 20-year-old Pendleton student ,
Michelle Mancini , was found in her car .
Police suspect her assailant
was probably hiding in the back seat .
In the meantime , the search continues
for Michael McDonald ,
the proprietor of this gas station where she was last seen .
Police are asking anyone with any information
on his whereabouts to contact them immediately .
This is David McAree reporting live .
- [ Parker ] Well , that 's horrible .
- Someone told me that she was listening
to my show when it happened .
I mean , my voice was probably the last thing she heard .
Can you imagine ?
- You guys , what if there is a lunatic on campus ?
- That 's fine with me .
I 'm hitting the half pipe at Kellington this weekend .
- Hey , did anyone here know her ?
She roomed in Daley .
- No . - No .
- Hello ?
Space cadet .
- Oh , no , I didn 't know her .
- Actually , you know , I did know her .
- You did ? - Yeah .
I 'll miss her , too , ' cause that girl gave great head .
( both laughing )
Get it , she gave great head .
Come on ! - That was good .
( upbeat music )
( hard rock music )
- Hey , Tosh .
Sorry about last night .
- Yeah ?
Well , don 't let it happen again .
♪ I know your life is empty ♪
♪ And you hate to face this world alone ♪
♪ So you 're searching for an angel ♪
♪ Someone who can make you whole ♪
- Here , you dropped these .
♪ I can not save you ♪
( phone line beeping )
Um , Tosh ?
Excuse me ?
♪ I can 't even save ♪
- This is my phone line too .
- [ Brenda ] Hey , it 's Brenda .
You seemed kind of weird this afternoon .
You okay , hon ?
Call me .
- [ Natalie 's Mom ] Natalie , it 's Mom .
Listen , sweetie , I 'm just calling to make sure you 're okay .
Isn 't it horrible about Michelle ?
Please call , okay ?
I love you .
( machine beeping )
( bell ringing ) ( distant laughing )
( knocking on door )
- Hey !
I was just in the neighborhood .
Thought I 'd drop by , see if you wanted to go to the house .
Parker said he 's gonna pierce Hootie 's nose .
- Hootie 's a dog .
- Yeah , there 's no reason he can 't be hip .
- No , that 's okay , Damon .
- What 's up , Natalie ?
You all right ?
- Yeah , I 'm fine .
- Listen , we don 't have to go hang out
with a bunch of drunken frat boys .
We could just go some place and talk .
I don 't really want this to get out around campus ,
but I can actually be a pretty good listener
every once in a while .
' Kay ?
- Okay .
- A little something to warm you up ?
- Sure .
Thanks .
( car engine sputtering )
- It 's a slight process .
♪ I don 't wanna wait ♪
Oh , God .
So you and Michelle were friends then ?
- [ Natalie ] Yeah .
- [ Damon ] So what happened ?
- [ Natalie ] I 'd really rather not talk about it anymore .
- It 's completely understandable .
If you don 't want to open up , that 's fine .
But I want you to know
that I know exactly what you 're going through .
- You do ?
- Sure .
I lost somebody close to me .
My girlfriend , she 's ...
She 's dead and ... - Oh , I 'm so sorry .
- No , it 's okay .
She was sick for awhile .
She had a syndrome and after that ,
I was afraid to get close to anybody for a long time ,
but then it hit me , you know .
Why am I being so selfish ?
I still have so much love inside of me left to give .
- You do ?
- Yeah , and Natalie , you 're in need of loving .
- I am ?
- Yeah .
You 're lonely .
You 're repressed .
You 're aching to break loose .
Those are the type of problems that only a man can fix .
- And , I suppose , you 're that man .
- Well , you know .
- Nice try , Damon .
That was a fairly good impersonation of a human being .
- I understand , you 're afraid .
But you don 't have to be afraid anymore , Natalie .
You don 't have to be afraid to love .
- Start the car right now .
- Okay , that hurt .
You know , I 'm just trying to help you out here .
You don 't have to act like such a bitch .
- ( scoffs ) It 's not an act .
Believe me .
- You sure you don 't wanna think this over ?
You know , ' cause I 'm all about healing , Natalie .
- One black eye or two , Damon ?
You decide .
- All right , fine .
I 'm gonna take a piss .
I 'll be right back .
- Pig .
♪ Won 't you tell me if you still believe that I am ♪
( animal screeching )
♪ Believe that I am ♪
( twig snapping )
( dramatic music )
Okay .
♪ All I needed was everything ♪
Damon ?
Shake it and let 's go .
( twig snapping )
( dramatic music ) ( Natalie screaming )
Come on , come on , come one !
( car engine sputtering )
Fuck .
( dramatic music )
Damon !
( loud thudding )
( Natalie screams )
( car engine sputtering ) Damon !
( faint whistling )
( Damon gasping )
- Natalie .
Don 't start the car .
( Damon coughing )
( loud thudding ) ( Natalie screaming )
( Damon screaming )
( ominous music )
( dramatic music )
( engine revving )
( Natalie screaming )
( glass shattering ) ( body thudding )
( dramatic music )
- This is the end of your rotten life ,
you motherfuckin ' dope pusher !
( movie gun firing )
It was easy for him
because he really didn 't believe it was coming .
But it ain 't gonna be easy for you
' cause you better believe this coming .
Girl , what 's wrong with you ?
- They killed him !
Somebody killed him !
It 's right past this bridge .
- [ Reese ] I don 't see nothing .
Are you sure this is it ?
- [ Natalie ] I don 't get it .
The car was ... - Here , huh ?
You don 't mind me asking ,
what the hell are you on ?
- Nothing !
The car was right here .
- Right here .
- Reese , I saw his body .
I touched it .
It 's probably the same person who killed Michelle Mancini .
- That 's impossible , baby .
The police arrested that gas station attendant
this afternoon .
- It was a mannequin , Natalie .
Damon uses it all the time to scare pledges during hazing .
He also has this life-size blow-up doll .
But you probably don 't wanna know about that .
- It wasn 't a mannequin , Parker .
Damon was dead .
- Come on , Nat .
Damon is the best practical joker
on this campus , all right ?
I mean , he once convinced a freshman
he was the middle Hanson brother just so he could get laid .
- Okay , Parker , shouldn 't he be here enjoying his handiwork ?
- Weekend snowboarding trip . - Oh , yeah .
- Some last-fling bachelor party
with some high school buddies .
Come on .
Whoa , whoa , wait a minute .
Scratching on the roof of the car .
Don 't you guys get it ?
Come on , just like that urban legend .
- What are you talking about ?
- Come on , Natalie .
Wexler talks about it every semester in class .
You know ?
Guy and a girl parked out in the woods , making out .
- You made out with him ?
- Guy steps out of the car and the girl starts
to hear these scratching noises on the roof .
It 's her dead boyfriend , hung from a tree .
Damon 's in the class .
He knew the myth , alright .
He must 've just planned the whole thing out .
Well , I thought it was the only way
a girl would ever say that he was hung .
Conniving bastard .
- Wait a second .
Isn 't there another story about a guy with an ax
hiding in a woman 's back seat ?
- Hello ?
My mom still checks the back seat before getting into a car .
- That 's how Michelle Mancini died .
- Oh , my God .
- What are you trying to say , Natalie ?
- It 's like someone out there is taking all these stories
and making them reality ?
- Well , then my big question is , what is he gonna do next ?
Huh ?
Maybe put spider eggs in bubble gum
or maybe ram a gerbil up a celebrity 's ass .
( Sasha snickering ) Come on !
Nat , give Damon a call up at Kellington , alright ?
You 'll see he 's there .
( hard rock music )
- Tosh , do you mind if I ... - What ?
- [ Natalie ] Never mind .
- [ Attendant ] Yeah , there was a blonde guy who arrived
with that group this morning .
Bachelor party or something .
- Okay , Damon Brooks , specifically .
Can you tell me if he checked in ?
- [ Attendant ] Oh , well , I really can 't tell you that .
The cabin 's not in his name ,
and it 's not on his credit card .
Look , I 'm happy to take the message ,
but I can 't guarantee that he 'll stop by to pick it up .
So whatever you want me ...
( clock bell dinging )
( door creaking )
- Hello ?
( faint creaking )
Is someone there ?
( light thudding )
( ominous music )
( creaking ) ( dramatic music )
( Natalie screaming )
- Hey , Nat , look what I found .
- What ?
- [ Sasha ] An early edition of Kama Sutra with illustrations .
You think Parker 'll get into it ?
- ( giggles ) Does he have a choice ?
- No .
What 's that ?
Oh .
Nat , don 't tell me you still think ...
- I don 't know .
This is it .
- Wait a second .
This is definitely not a myth .
- [ Natalie ] What ?
- The Gang High Beam Initiation .
It happens all the time .
Gang members drive around at night
with their headlights off .
And when someone goes to flash their high beams
to warn them , they kill them .
That 's why I never warn anybody about anything when I drive .
Anyway , I gotta go .
I got some homework .
- Okay , see you later . - Bye .
♪ I got an itch in my cosmic . Pocket and it won 't go away ♪
♪ Instead of dragging your swamp for your lost love ♪
♪ Come to me I 'm your living crop circle , yeah ♪
♪ I 'll curl you up in my flame pit , baby ♪
♪ Until you 're way over done ♪
♪ I came up from the ground , I came down from the sky ♪
♪ And I 'm grabbing her knees like a worm with a mission ♪
♪ ' Cause I 'm made out of salt and I 'm made out of coal ♪
♪ And I live like a king in a show mercial ♪
♪ Instead of make you a man , make you a monkey ♪
( intense music )
( Tosh gasping )
- Sounds like Elvira 's raising more
than just the dead in there .
- Thanks for the warning .
( Tosh moaning ) ( dramatic music )
- [ Tosh ] Natalie !
( Tosh moaning )
- [ Natalie ] I 'm sorry .
I 'm not looking .
( Tosh moaning )
( Tosh gasping )
( light music )
♪ My eyes and sleep ♪
♪ For years ♪
♪ Tell me that it 's only ♪
( clock bells ringing )
( eerie music )
( dramatic music )
( Natalie screaming )
- Hey !
Better check her pulse .
She 's looked like that for years .
- Hey , Paul .
- [ Paul ] How is she ?
- I don 't know .
I haven 't had a chance to talk to her yet .
- All right , I 'll see you later .
- Natalie , we know this is difficult for you ,
but we need to understand why if you heard moaning ,
you didn 't turn on the lights ?
- I 'd walked in on Tosh having sex before .
It wasn 't something I cared to see again .
- So you never actually saw anyone there .
- Well , I sensed that ...
- No , no , honey , did you see anyone in the room ?
- No .
- Natalie , did you know Tosh was manic-depressive ?
- She painted half the room black .
I had a pretty good idea .
- There are no signs of foul play here .
No forced entry .
- What are you saying ?
- It appears to be a tragic suicide .
- No .
Tosh didn 't kill herself .
There was someone else in that room .
I mean , aren 't you glad you didn 't turn on the lights ,
for Christ 's sake ?
- A very morbid suicide note .
- Honey , I am so sorry .
Are you all right ?
Of course not .
Stupid question .
I mean , who would 've thought
she would do something like that ?
I mean , she 's weird and everything , but .
Okay , Natalie , you wanna go get some coffee and talk ?
- No , I just gotta be alone right now .
( sirens blaring )
- Hey .
- I know that this is a really bad time for you
but I gotta ask you a couple of questions .
- Hell no , I 'm not doing any interviews .
- Hey , if it makes you feel any better ,
I don 't wanna talk about Tosh , okay .
I just wanted to know
if you can tell me a little bit about this .
- [ Natalie ] How did you get that ?
- I contacted Michelle 's high school , your high school .
Now , why didn 't you tell me you knew her ?
- So you could exploit her death more than you already have .
- Hey , look , I 'm just doing my job here , okay ?
What am I supposed to do ?
Turn my back on a murder ?
Or a suicide ?
- It wasn 't a suicide , Paul !
- What are you talking about ? - She was murdered .
She was murdered just like Michelle .
Just like Damon .
- Oh , boy , Damon ?
I don 't know what 's going on here
but , you know , if you want , we can go somewhere and talk .
Off the record .
( phone ringing )
- You don 't believe me either .
- That 's not what I 'm saying .
It 's just that the idea
of an urban legend serial killer ?
It 's a stretch .
- But don 't you think it 's possible ?
- Yeah , it 's possible .
But maybe the gas station attendant killed Michelle .
Maybe Damon 's snowboarding .
And maybe Tosh just killed herself .
- Okay .
- If it is true , why like this ?
Why now ?
- Tonight 's the 25th anniversary .
- What 's that got to do with anything ?
- The Stanley Hall Massacre .
- I tom you , that story is not true .
- Are you sure ?
- All right , if there 's any truth to Stanley Hall ,
it 'd be in here .
- So this is where you research all your lurid articles .
- Reality is lurid , all right ?
I 'm only the messenger .
71-72 , ' 74 .
That 's weird .
' 73 's not here .
Hey .
How long you been workin ' here ?
- Too damn long .
- You know anything about Stanley Hall ?
- I don 't know what you 're talking about .
- Did anyone die there ?
Please .
We really need to know .
- Talk to Wexler .
- It 's his office hours .
He should be here .
- Here , watch out .
Just a second .
Would you look at that ?
- So do they teach you this in class ?
- I dropped Journalism Ethics early in the semester .
Wasn 't helping my G.P.A.
( sharp dramatic music )
( eerie music )
- Paul ?
- Oh , shit .
( door handle jiggling )
- Is he gone ? - Yeah .
Shew .
- Something I can help you with ?
- You two break in to a professor 's office
and then have the audacity to accuse him of murder ?
- We found the ax .
- That is a prop I use in my folklore class .
How can you even suggest that I had
anything to do with that girl 's death ?
- Why don 't you tell us about the Stanley Hall Massacre ?
- Professor Wexler , Reese ,
may I have a moment alone with them ?
Natalie , after our talk this morning ,
I decided to take a look at your personal file .
Probation for reckless endangerment ?
- It was just for a year .
I 'd already been accepted here .
- Which was lucky .
Since we don 't usually accept students
with a criminal record .
As for you , young man ,
you 're off the paper effective immediately .
- No , no , you can 't do that , okay ?
Read the charter .
The dean can 't dictate editorial policy .
- I didn 't fire you .
Your editor did .
We spoke an hour ago .
Have a good weekend .
- Hey !
What was all that about ?
Reckless endangerment ?
We 're not exactly talking about
running a stop sign here , are we , Natalie ?
- I really don 't wanna talk about it .
- Oh , okay , what do you want to talk about ?
My career options without a body of writing samples ?
Because for your information , Natalie ,
they 're kind of limited .
- It was in high school , Paul .
It 's over .
- Hey .
Look .
Does this have something to do with Michelle Mancini ?
Hey , I just wanna know what 's going on here
' cause I don 't know if I buy it anymore .
I don 't know if I ever bought it .
- It 's gonna be a wet one out there tonight , folks .
The storm is expected to bring four inches of rain
and 30-mile-per-hour winds throughout most of New England .
Local authorities are advising everyone
to please stay indoors .
If you do decide to go out though ,
make sure you grab a slicker .
( intense music )
- Brenda !
Brenda !
( glass shattering )
- Natalie , nothing is gonna happen to me .
But why do you keep doing this to yourself ?
Look at you .
You 've gotta stop this .
- I knew Michelle Mancini .
We went to high school together .
We hadn 't spoken in two years .
- Why ?
- We were in my car one night .
Michelle was driving .
The story about the gang high beam initiation
had been going around .
Michelle wanted to play a practical joke
so she turned the headlights off
and waited for the first car to pass by and flash us .
When someone finally did she made a U-turn
and started chasing him ,
flashing her high beams , laughing .
I was laughing , too , at first .
But then we started going really fast .
I wanted to tell her to stop
but I just sat there .
And then the other car lost control and ran off the road .
He was our age .
By the time the ambulance came , he was already dead .
The courts were lenient with us .
We just got probation .
I was never able to forgive her for what she did .
I guess I couldn 't forgive myself
for not doing something more to stop it .
- Oh , my God .
How awful .
For everyone .
- I don 't know , I think I should just go home
for a few ... - Natalie , come on .
You need to be relaxed and have some fun
and come to the party , okay ?
Please ?
- Okay , promise you won 't leave me alone .
- I promise .
Unless , of course , I hook up with
some cute , little blue-eyed journalist .
Then you might have to fend for yourself . ( laughs )
( car alarm chirping ) ( ominous music )
- Don 't do that . - Sorry , Dean .
Little jumpy ?
- No , not at all .
I was just thinking .
- Me too .
It wouldn 't be a bad idea to add on a few extra guards
this weekend just in case .
- In case what ?
- Well , after that suicide
and what happened to the Mancini girl ,
now I 'm having trouble locating another student ,
a boy named Damon Brooks .
He 's been missing for some days now .
- Missing ?
He 's not missing .
It 's the weekend .
He 's probably shacked up in some motel
with a girl or a guy or a farm animal .
Whatever .
Weren 't you ever 18 ?
- Not that kind of 18 .
- My point is I don 't want you overreacting .
Don 't contact anyone without my permission .
No parents .
No police .
Is that understood ?
- Understood .
Good night , sir .
( object clanking )
( dramatic music ) ( groaning )
( crowd chanting ) ( thunder booming )
- Go !
Come on , boy !
There you go !
That 's my boy !
( crowd cheering ) I love you !
- Hey , hey , listen .
( woman screaming )
That scream , that 's an actual cry for help
by a girl being murdered .
- You 're kidding me ?
- No !
That 's why it sounds so real
because it was lifted off a 911 tape .
- That 's great . - Yeah .
♪ Rollercoaster ♪
♪ Woo hoo hoo ♪
- Hey , miss thang ! - Hey , I made it !
And already , I 'm starting to regret it .
- I 'm gonna go get something to drink .
You want anything ?
- A beer . - Okay .
Be right back .
- Stanley Hall 's not a legend .
There was one survivor that night .
It makes perfect sense .
Pendleton covered up Stanley Hall and Wexler ,
so long as he keeps his mouth shut ,
he gets a job for life .
- Why would he do it ?
- It eats at him .
And probably every year around this time ,
he goes a little wacko .
This year , off the charts .
- Well , then , we have to call the police right away
before it happens again .
- I already tried .
Dean Adams beat me to it .
They said he warned ' em to expect some prank calls tonight .
He even gave ' em our names .
Look .
I 'm sorry I doubted you before .
What ?
Hey .
- What is he trying to do to me ?
I 'm so scared .
- Hey .
Listen to me .
Nothing 's gonna happen to you , okay ?
I promise .
- You don 't waste any time , do you , Natalie ?
- Brenda . - Here .
It 's light . - Oh , shit .
- What was all that about ?
- I screwed up .
♪ Throw back a bottle of beer ♪
♪ Zoot suit riot ♪
♪ Riot ♪
♪ Pull a comb through your coal black hair ♪
( Brenda softly crying )
( intense music ) - Jesus !
You trying to give me a heart attack here ?
The building 's off-limits after 10 : 00 .
Good night to you too .
( glass shattering )
Hello ?
( dramatic music )
( Reese screams )
Oh !
What ?
♪ You keep coming around ♪
- Hey , Parker .
Let me talk to you for a second .
Look , you might wanna end this party a little early .
- What ?
- Natalie was right all along .
- Say no more , say no more .
Everybody , listen up !
No , no , no , no listen .
Turn the music down .
Listen , everybody .
Paul here , he thinks we should end the party .
- [ Crowd ] No .
- No , no , no , no .
Tell everybody why , why they should go home .
- There 's a killer on campus .
( crowd laughing )
- And let me guess .
This killer is offing people based on urban legends .
- Yeah , that 's right .
- Well , I 've got a legend
that you may or you may not have heard of .
I see this mediocre Woodward and Bernstein wanna-be
realized , shit , I 'm gonna graduate in a couple of weeks
and end up writing gardening tips
for Martha Stewart 's Living .
( crowd laughing ) Hang on .
Unless I get a really hot story .
Something that really flies .
I got it .
I 'll take advantage of my homicidal instincts
and I 'll start killing people
in a trendy , attention-getting , cover-story kind of way ,
basing them on urban legends .
- [ Paul ] Why don 't you have another drink ?
- Paul ?
Maybe you 're the one that should leave
and let everybody else have a good time .
( crowd cheering ) Right ?
- You stay here .
I 'm gonna go get some help , all right ?
- Parker , why do you always have to be such a jerk ?
- I was just messing around .
- I 'm gonna go to the radio station , okay ?
- Hey , hey , who 's my girl ?
Who 's my girl ?
That 's my girl !
( Sasha screaming )
- Let 's go .
( phone ringing )
- Hello ?
Hello ? !
- [ Killer ] You 're gonna die tonight .
- Oh , really ?
I see .
The call 's coming from inside the house .
Could it be an urban legend ?
Am I right ?
Hello ?
Hey , don 't get shy on me all of a sudden , fuck face .
This is the one about the baby-sitter , right ?
She 's getting those scary , harassing phone calls .
When she traces them back ,
they 're coming from inside the house , right ?
But asswipe aren 't you forgetting something ?
I 'm not baby-sitting any kids .
- [ Killer ] Wrong legend .
This is the one about the old lady
who dries her wet dog in the microwave .
( thunder booming ) ( ominous music )
( microwave beeping )
- Goddamn , fucking sick , motherfucker !
Hootie .
Fuck !
Wanna fuck with me ?
( Parker moaning )
- [ Operator ] Are you sure it 's blood ?
- Yes , I 'm sure it 's blood !
I 'm covered in it !
- [ Operator ] Due to the storm ,
all units are presently responding to calls .
A unit has been called ...
- You know what really chaps my hide ?
It 's the way you pledge an oath to serve and protect .
And then you don 't give a rat 's ass
when something really happens .
- [ Operator ] Hold , please .
- I 'll do it myself .
- [ Paul ] This is Paul .
Leave a message .
- So let me get this straight .
You guys just tried out this new sexual position
and now you 're stuck . - I 'm not stuck .
He is .
- [ Man ] Just relax and stop clenching .
- [ Woman ] I saw this happen to dogs once .
It 's so humiliating .
- All right , you guys ,
this is what you 're gonna do , okay ?
( phone line clicking ) Hello ?
Hello ?
Are you guys there ?
( dramatic music ) ( Sasha screaming )
Help me !
Somebody help me !
( Sasha screaming )
- Something 's happening .
- No .
She 's doing a performance art piece
to commemorate the massacre .
( Sasha screaming )
Help me !
Oh , my God !
Please !
- She 's good .
I got chills .
( Sasha screaming )
- No !
Somebody !
Someone , please !
Help !
( dramatic music ) ( Sasha groaning )
My God !
( sirens blaring )
Please , help me !
Natalie !
Natalie , help me !
( door slamming ) ( dramatic music )
- No !
- Please , I don 't wanna die .
I don 't wanna die .
- No !
No !
Paul !
Sasha 's dead !
I just saw her and the killer .
- All right , all right .
Where did this happen ? - The radio station .
- Jesus .
Come on .
Why did you leave ?
I thought I tom you to stay at the house .
Oh , shit .
- Where were you ?
- Running all over campus .
Trying to find help .
The dean is gone .
I can 't find Reese anywhere .
It 's dead .
Goddamn storm .
We 're gonna get the hell out of here .
Gotta get off campus and find some help .
- What are you doing ?
- I was just making sure the ...
- I told you the phones were dead .
Hey , Natalie .
I 'm on your side .
Okay ?
Let 's get out of here .
We 'll go into town .
We 'll find a phone .
( Natalie screaming )
- What 's happening ?
I heard Sasha on the radio .
- She 's dead . - Oh , my God .
Are you sure ?
- Come on , we 're out of here .
- What ?
- Hello ?
( Reese gasps )
Dean Adams , this is Reese .
Hello ?
Are you there ?
You have my number .
Use it .
- ( sniffs ) Do you smell something ?
- No .
- Hey , maybe we should stop over at that gas station ,
see if the phones work .
- Okay .
Fine .
Be right back . - Okay .
- Oh , it does reek in here .
- Yeah .
- Natalie , I 'm sorry that I acted
like such a jerk about you and Paul .
You two like each other .
Then you should be together .
( phone ringing )
( Natalie gasping ) ( Debra coughing )
( both screaming )
Like I said , he 's all yours .
( intense music )
- [ Paul ] Natalie !
- Natalie !
Where are we going ? - Back to campus .
- Brenda !
( Brenda screaming )
Brenda !
- [ Paul ] Natalie !
( dramatic music )
- [ Natalie ] Stop !
Stop !
- What 's wrong ? - Someone 's after me .
- Get in . - Okay .
- You okay ?
- No .
- Got a coat right there .
Ain 't gonna bite ya .
- Okay , just let me out right here .
- What ?
( door handle jiggling ) What are you doing ?
- Please , just let me out .
- It won 't open from the inside .
( door handle jiggling ) Stop that !
What 's wrong with you ?
Idiot kids . ( switch clicking )
- No !
It 's him !
Keep going , keep going , keep going !
Come on , come on .
Just keep going , keep going !
Faster !
( both screaming )
( loudly thudding )
( brakes squealing )
( buzzer buzzing ) Hello ?
Is anybody there ?
Help !
Can you hear me ?
- Hello ?
- [ Debra ] Somebody help me !
Oh , God !
( ominous music ) ( Debra screaming )
Somebody help me !
( Debra screaming )
He 's gonna kill me !
Please !
Please , somebody help me !
( Brenda yells )
Please !
( ominous music )
( door slamming ) ( Natalie screaming )
( body thudding ) ( Natalie screaming )
( door squeaking )
Gotcha !
I must say , Natalie , you have proved
your friendship to me ,
coming all the way out here to rescue me
without even a little pepper spray to defend yourself .
Very endearing .
( muffled speaking ) Excuse me ?
I 'm sorry , but I can 't understand
a thing you 're saying , doll .
Now , if I remove the gag
you have got to promise me that you won 't scream .
Lord knows I had enough of that with Sasha .
- You 're fucking crazy !
- ( laughs ) I prefer the term eccentric but , yeah .
I guess you could say I 'm a little nutty .
- Why ?
Why ?
Why !
You still haven 't figured it out , have you ?
Well , lucky for you , Miss Thang ,
I 've got a visual aid .
There I am , Natalie ,
with my boyfriend , the love of my life .
Have you found the love of your life yet , Natalie ?
Course not .
You 're too self-involved to bother .
Pic ring any bells , Nat ?
- Oh , my God .
- Ding , ding , ding , ding , cling !
His name was David Evans .
The one you and your friend decided
to have a little fun with that night .
You know , David and I were gonna get married
that summer right after graduation .
He didn 't have enough money to buy me a ring yet
so he got me this instead .
The night you took him away from me !
- Brenda , I wasn 't ...
- You weren 't driving but it was in your car
and you were there , Natalie !
Now , didn 't you tell me that you were having
a little difficulty forgiving yourself , Natalie ?
Well , I thought , as a friend ,
I could help you out in that department . ( laughs )
Payback 's a bitch !
Isn 't it , Natalie ?
- Brenda , please , you need to get help .
- I have already tried therapy !
Obviously , it did me no good , Natalie .
And I must say ,
I am kind of enjoying all this ,
playing with your pretty little head .
You used an urban legend to kill my boyfriend , Natalie .
And now ... - What are you gonna do ?
- Oh , just my favorite U.L.
The Kidney Heist .
You do know this one , don 't you , Natalie ?
Guy gets picked up by a woman at a bar .
She takes him back to her hotel room .
She fixes him a drink .
Boom !
He 's knocked out .
When he wakes up , he 's in a bathtub full of ice
and he realizes that one of his kidneys has been removed .
Supposedly they sell them on the black market .
I don 't think it 's ever actually happened though .
Till tonight .
- You won 't get away with this .
- Natalie , of course I will .
I 've got the perfect murder
in the trunk of Paul 's car .
Wexler !
- You 're sick .
- Professor does away with his students ,
then kills himself in the same manner
as the course he teaches .
It 's beautiful .
It 's so fucking clean , isn 't it ?
Well , enough chat , Nat .
Now , I 'm sorry but I don 't have any anesthesia .
I guess you 'll just have to bite down real hard
on that gag and hope that you go into shock soon .
- Please , don 't do this .
- Oh .
Don 't you wanna be an urban legend ?
All your friends are now .
Ouch !
Stupid bitch !
I 'm really gonna enjoy watching you bleed to death .
Now , is this your kidney ?
Or is that the liver ?
I was always such a dope in anatomy .
Well , who cares , right ?
First organ I see , I 'm just gonna grab it .
( muffled screaming )
- Drop the weapon !
- Oh , great .
Rent-A-Cop to the rescue .
- Put your hands up .
Get up against the wall .
You loony psycho bitch .
It 's all right , sugar .
It 's gonna be okay .
Move it !
Don 't you move .
( dramatic music )
( gun firing )
- Don 't you fucking move .
Shit .
Bullet through the head .
Not exactly an urban legend , but in the essence of time .
- It 's not gonna bring him back , Brenda .
- I know that , Natalie , but it will bring
a devastated little Paul right into my arms .
I 'll have him , and he 'll have his Pulitzer .
What did you think , Natalie .
I was gonna let you take two men out of my life ?
( clapping )
- Very well done .
I couldn 't have planned it better myself .
- Really ? - Oh , yeah .
I mean , I thought I was screwed
after Natalie here fucked it up for me
with the clean , but this ,
this is just what I need .
A few things though , okay ?
- I 'm listening .
- Well .
I need some details for my article .
You know , about how Wexler did each one .
Details only you could give me .
- It would be great for your career .
And we would be so fucking hot together , Paul .
- And I 'd be very grateful .
So why don 't you give me the gun .
I 'll take care of the rest .
- You 're cute , Paul .
But you 're not that fucking cute .
Now , which one of you do I kill first ?
Eenie .
Meenie .
Miney .
( gun firing )
- Moe .
- What , are you gonna shoot me , Natalie ?
Huh ?
What kind of friend are you ?
( Brenda screaming )
( gun firing )
( light music ) ( Natalie rapidly breathing )
- Natalie , give me the gun .
Come here .
You all right ? - No .
( Reese coughing )
- Reese .
- Thought I 'd have to wait to be a cop
before a bullet ever hit me .
- Just stay down .
We 're gonna go get some help .
- All right . - All right ?
- Come on . - Quick .
( thunder crashing )
- [ Natalie ] Do you think Reese 'll be okay ?
- [ Paul ] Reese is gonna be fine .
Paramedics are on the way .
- This 'll become a legend , too , you know .
It 'll change a little from person to person , of course .
Brenda will become a guy .
You 'll become a cop .
And I 'll end up in some insane asylum .
- So if this is an urban legend ,
at what point do we get to the twist ?
( intense music )
( car skidding )
( Paul groaning ) ( women screaming )
Natalie !
( grass shattering ) ( Brenda screaming )
( sirens blaring )
- The river was such a mess because of the storm ,
it washed away the body .
The thing of it is they never found a body .
It wasn 't there .
( everyone laughing ) - Bullshit .
- It 's true .
Happened right here at Ashton .
I swear to God .
- Man , that is a stupid story you hear
at every campus in the northeast .
- Exactly , I mean , where 's your proof ?
- Were you even listening ?
It all keeps getting covered up .
Think about it .
Who would enroll at Murder U ?
- Yeah , and you know what ?
Natalie ; she 's my old roommate 's cousin .
- And Brenda 's the girl in that Noxzema commercial .
- Look , does anybody here believe me ?
- Not a chance . - No .
- I believe you .
- Thank you .
- But you didn 't tell it right .
- I didn 't ? - ( laughs ) Not at all .
Okay , listen up , guys .
' Cause this is how the story really goes .
( scary intense music )
( eerie music )
♪ Glory ♪